Together till the end
Kursk is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Thomas Vinterberg.
Barents Sea, August 12th, 2000.
During a Russian naval exercise, and after suffering a serious accident, the
K-141 Kursk submarine sinks with 118 crew members on board.
While the few sailors who are still alive barely manage to survive, their families push for accurate information and a
British officer struggles to obtain from the Russian government a permit to attempt a rescue before it is late.
But general incompetence are against all their efforts.
Mikhail Averin, played by Matthias Schoenaerts.
Tanya Averina, played by Léa Seydoux.
Admiral Vyacheslav Grudzinsky, played by Peter Simonischek.
Admiral Vladimir Petrenko, played by Max von Sydow.
Anton Markov, played by August Diehl.
Commodore David Russell, played by Colin Firth.
Kursk (UK: Kursk: The Last Mission, US: The Command) is a 2018 disaster drama-thriller film directed by Thomas
Vinterberg, based on Robert Moore's book A Time to Die, about the true story of the 2000 Kursk submarine disaster.
It stars Matthias Schoenaerts, Léa Seydoux, Peter Simonischek,
August Diehl, Max von Sydow, and Colin Firth.
It was the last of von Sydow's films to be released during his lifetime.
The film explores themes of submarine, based on true story,
struggle for survival, russian politics, russian history.
The tone is emotional and intense.